cashconverters.co.uk 2016-12-03

# Privacy Policy | Cash Converters

## Cash Converters (UK) Ltd  
Privacy Policy

### PART 1: OVERVIEW

#### About Us

We are Cash Converters (UK) Limited, a company registered in England and Wales with company number 03096334. Our registered office is Cash Converters (UK) Ltd, Innovation House, Aston Lane South, Preston Brook, WA7 3FY.

#### About this Policy

This privacy policy applies to any use we make of your personal details collected by us, whether through this website or as a result of your use of this website, or when you otherwise apply for or use any of our products and services, including any application you make for a loan (whether or not successful) through our website [www.cashconverters.co.uk](http://www.cashconverters.co.uk/ "Cash Converters UK") or otherwise.

This Privacy Policy explains our commitment to protecting your information and privacy. It also explains how we use the information you provide to us when you visit our website or when you contact us or use our products and services.

Please read this Privacy Policy before submitting any information about yourself to us. By providing us with details, whether through the website or otherwise, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

#### Definitions

In this Privacy Policy, **Personal Information** means any information about you from which you can be personally identified and which relates to you. This may include your name, address, email address, home telephone number and mobile phone number, work address, work e-mail address and telephone number, your age and date of birth, your employment status, your country of residence and nationality, names and contact telephone numbers for any alternative contacts that you provide to us, financial details (including details of any benefits), username, password and other information which you may disclose to us. In certain circumstances, we may also be provided with limited health information, such as details of any physical or mental health issues or conditions which may affect how we communicate with you or your ability to make payments. Personal information about physical or mental health issues or conditions is referred to in this Privacy Policy as “ **sensitive personal information** ”. Where sensitive personal information is provided by you, this is processed by us on the basis that you have provided us with your express consent to the use of your sensitive personal information by us for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. We may also collect details of your visits to the website including, but not limited to, domain name and shortened IP address, browser version, operating system, the URL you came from, the pages visited within the website, the URL to which you go upon leaving the website, and whether you return to our website.

By providing us with contact details for your place of employment, you confirm that we may contact you at work using the details provided.

#### Why we need your Personal Information

The main reason we use your Personal Information is to provide you with the products or services you have requested, to deal with your queries, or consider or process any loan or other application you make and to collect any payments when due. If you apply to us for a loan, we will collect some necessary Personal Information about you from other people, such as credit reference agencies and your employer so we can check details you have provided to us and your credit worthiness.

#### How we use your Personal Information

We may share your details with group and external service providers who help us to provide agreed services to you, such as website hosting providers or companies hosting consolidated customer databases. We may also share your details where necessary with other members of our group of companies and its franchisees where needed for management authorisations or approvals, to administer our systems, investigations or where they are involved in the financing or securing of arrangements you have requested.

For certain products, we will make searches about you at credit reference agencies who will supply us with credit information, for use in the assessment of credit products and other information, as well as information from the Electoral Register, for the purpose of verifying your identity. The agencies will record details of the search type, credit or identification, whether or not this application proceeds. We may use credit-scoring methods to assess this application and to verify your identity. We may also contact your employer to verify your employment status. Credit searches and other information which is provided to us and/or the credit reference agencies, about you and those with whom you are linked financially may be used by us and other companies if credit decisions are made about you, or other members of your household. Any of this information may also be used for identification purposes, debt tracing, debt recovery and the prevention of money laundering as well as the management of your account.

For certain products, we may make periodic searches of credit reference agencies to manage your account with us, to take decisions regarding credit, including whether to make credit available or to continue or extend existing credit. The searches will not be seen or used by lenders to assess your ability to obtain credit. Where you borrow or may borrow from us, we may give details of your account and how you manage it to credit reference agencies. If you borrow and do not repay in full and on-time, we may tell credit reference agencies who will record the outstanding debt. Please see Part 2 of this privacy policy for further details.  
We will retain information on unsuccessful or aborted applications for our products and services for up to six years following the application.

#### Further Uses

We may also use details to ask you to complete surveys about our website or services, unless you object, so that we can adjust and improve our services as necessary.  
We and other group companies and franchisees may also use your Personal Information:

    * to improve our products and services;
    * internal record keeping;
    * to communicate with you by e-mail, telephone, SMS or post, either regarding the services you have requested or other matters regarding transactions between you and us or your customer relationship with us;
    * to contact you by e-mail, telephone, SMS or post in order to share information with you about products, services and events from Cash Converters, other group companies and franchisees that may be of interest to you;
    * statistical analysis;
    * fraud prevention, prevention of money laundering and other unlawful activity;
    * debt collection and debt tracing including disclosure of your data to any person to whom your debt may be assigned;
    * to deal with internal administration, to train our advisors, to perform our contract terms and to enforce them, to monitor our performance and to improve our services and facilities, to exercise and defend legal rights and obligations, to deal with regulatory obligations and police / authority / regulator enquiries and investigations, to comply with legally binding requests for information, such as a court order, and to carry out audits;
    * if we undergo re-organisation or are sold to a third party, in which case you agree that any Personal Information we hold about you may be transferred to that re-organised entity or third party;
    * to the extent otherwise required or permitted by law.

We will not otherwise transfer, disclose, sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission to do so or are otherwise required or permitted to do so by law.

#### Direct Marketing and your Preferences

We may wish to provide you with information about new products, promotions, special offers of Cash Converters, group companies and franchisees and other information which may be of interest to you and invite you to take part in market research. This communication may occur by post, telephone, email or SMS (unless you have asked us not to do so). We will obtain your consent where we are required to do so in accordance with applicable law.

We will ensure that any direct marketing or market research that you receive or are contacted about by electronic means will provide a simple means for you to refuse further marketing. For example, in emails it may provide you with an ‘unsubscribe’ link, or an email address to which you can send an opt-out request. We will stop any marketing to which you object or withdraw your consent to within a reasonable period, in order to allow sufficient time for the change to be administered. You can change your mind at any time about marketing by informing us by telephone on 0800 1300 370. In such cases Cash Converters would not necessarily remove all your personal data from its database(s) but would note and respect your changed direct marketing preferences.

#### Third party personal information

If you provide personal information about someone else (such as an alternative contact) then you should not do so without their permission. By providing us with someone else’s personal information you confirm that you have their consent to do so. Where information is provided by you about someone else, or someone discloses information about you, it may be added to any personal information that is already held by us and it will be used in the ways described in this agreement.

#### Will my personal information be transferred abroad?

The personal information you provide to us is processed in the UK. It may be transferred to other group companies and to franchisees as described in previous paragraphs. Some of the companies to whom your personal information will be disclosed are located outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”), in countries which do not provide the same level of protection to personal information (such as Australia and the United States). We will take steps to ensure that your personal information will be afforded the level of protection required of us under applicable data protection legislation and this notice.

#### How to get copies of or amend the information we collect

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998 at any time. A small fee will be payable, currently £10. If you would like a copy of the information held about you please write to: Group Compliance Officer, Cash Converters UK Ltd, Innovation House, Aston Lane South, Preston Brook, WA7 3FY.

You have the right of access to your personal records held by credit and fraud agencies. If you would like to have details of the agencies we use please telephone us on 0800 1300 370.

#### Cookies

Please see our separate [Cookies Policy](http://www.cashconverters.co.uk/terms-and-conditions/cookies-on-the-cash-converters-website/ "Cash Converters UK Cookies Policy") for information about how we use cookies on our website and how you may exercise your preferences around the use of cookies.

**Cookie Name** | **Cookie Type/Duration** | **Category** | **Purpose**  
---|---|---|---  
Session ID as set by IIS | Session | Strictly necessary / functionality | Cookies for the storing of user data during a session.  Associates a user with their application.  
Cookie message | Persistent for 2 months | Functionality | Identifies when a customer has acknowledged the cookie message (at the top of the website) to prevent it reappearing.  
Google analytics:  
__utma  
__utmb  
__utmc  
__utmz | _Persistent for up to 2 years_  
2 years  
30 mins  
Session  
6 months | Performance | These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often.  
  
#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Please check this Privacy Policy regularly for changes. We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our practices and services. When we post changes to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the “Last Updated” date at the bottom of this Privacy Policy.

If we make any material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share your Personal Information, we will notify you by sending an email to the email address you most recently provided us in your account or registration (unless we do not have such an email address), and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our website. We recommend that you check our website from time to time to inform yourself of any changes in this Privacy Policy or any of our other policies.

If we add new cookies to our website, change the data collected by current cookies, or what we use that data for, we will let you know the next time you visit our website and ask for your consent to their use.

Last Updated: 16/08/13

### PART 2: CREDIT REFERENCING

#### General Information

If you apply for a loan from us, we will perform searches with credit reference agencies. If you borrow and do not repay in full and on time, we may tell credit reference agencies who will record the outstanding debt.

We will ask for your consent before passing details about you to any credit reference agencies. If you no not give us your consent, we will not proceed with your application.

The information below tells you about how credit reference agencies, Cash Converters  
and other lenders use your Personal Information.

**What is a credit reference agency?**  
Credit reference agencies (CRAs) collect and maintain information on consumers’ and businesses’ credit behaviour, on behalf of lenders in the UK.

**What is a fraud prevention agency?**  
Fraud Prevention Agencies (FPAs) collect, maintain and share information on known and suspected fraudulent activity. Some CRAs also act as FPAs.

**Why do you use them when I have applied to you?**  
Although you have applied to us and we will check our own records, we will also contact CRAs to get information on your credit behaviour with other organisations. This will help us make the best possible assessment of your overall situation before we make a decision.

**Where do they get information from?**  
Publicly available information sources such as

  * The Electoral Register at Local Authorities
  * County Court Judgments from Registry Trust
  * Bankruptcy information from the Insolvency Service
  * Fraud information from fraud prevention agencies
  * Credit information comes from information on applications to banks, building societies and credit card companies

**How will I know if my Personal Information is sent to a CRA or FPA?**  
You will be told when you apply for a loan if your data will be supplied. The next section tells you how, when and why we will search at CRAs and what we will do with the information we obtain from them. We will also tell you if we plan to send payment history information on you, if you have one, to CRAs. You can ask at any time for the name of the CRAs and FPAs we use.

**Why is my Personal Information used in this way?**  
We and other organisations want to make the best possible decisions we can, in order to make sure that you will be able to repay us. Some organisations may also use the information to check your identity. In this way we can ensure we all make responsible decisions. At the same time we also want to make decisions quickly and easily and, by using up to date information, provided electronically, we are able to make the most reliable and fair decisions possible.

**Who controls what CRAs can do with my Personal Information?**  
All organisations that collect and process personal data are regulated by the Data Protection Act 1998, overseen by Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). All credit reference agencies are in regular dialogue with the ICO. Use of the Electoral Register is controlled under the Representation of the People Act 2000.

**Can just anyone see my Personal Information held at CRAs?**  
No, access to your information is very strictly controlled and only those that are entitled to do so may see it. Usually that will only be with your agreement or if there is a legal requirement to do so.

#### Applying to us for a loan

We will search at credit reference agencies and at fraud prevention agencies for information on you and we will send the information you supply to us as part of the loan application to the credit reference agencies.

If you give us false or inaccurate information and we suspect fraud, we will record this and may also pass this information to financial and other organisations involved in fraud prevention to protect us, them and our respective customers from theft and fraud.

With the information we obtain from the credit reference agencies we will:

  * assess your application for credit
  * verify your identity
  * undertake checks for the prevention and detection of fraud and money laundering
  * undertake periodic statistical analysis or testing to ensure the accuracy of existing and future products and services

We may also use scoring methods to assess your application and to verify your identity. Any or all of these processes may be automated.

#### After you have a loan from us

Where you borrow or may borrow from us, we will give certain Personal Information about you to credit reference agencies. If you borrow and do not repay in full and on time, we will tell credit reference agencies. We may make periodic searches of our records, credit reference and fraud prevention agencies to manage your loan with us, to take decisions regarding your identity and also credit, including whether to make credit available or to continue or extend existing credit.

If you have borrowed from us and do not make payments that you owe us, we will trace your whereabouts and recover payment. To help us do this, we may share your Personal Information with third parties who assist us with tracing, debt collection and debt enforcement.

#### About Credit Reference Agencies

When credit reference agencies receive a search from us they will place a search ‘footprint’ on your credit file whether or not this application proceeds. If the search was for a credit application the record of that search (but not the name of the organisation that carried it out) may be seen by other organisations when you apply for credit in the future.

The credit reference agencies will also supply us with:

  * credit information such as previous applications
  * public information such as County Court Judgments and bankruptcies
  * electoral register information
  * fraud prevention information

If you borrow and do not repay in full and on time, credit reference agencies will record the outstanding debt. Records shared with credit reference agencies remain on file for 6 years after they are closed whether settled by you or defaulted.

#### How credit reference agencies use your Personal Information

The information which we, other organisations and fraud prevention agencies provide to the credit reference agencies about you may be supplied by credit reference agencies to other organisations and used by them to:

  * make decisions on credit
  * trace your whereabouts and recover payment if you do not make payments you owe
  * conduct checks for the prevention and detection of crime including fraud and money laundering
  * undertake statistical analysis and system testing

Your data may also be used for other purposes for which you give your specific permission or, in very limited circumstances, when required by law or where permitted under the terms of the Data Protection Act 1998. Your data may also be used to offer you other products.

Credit references agencies will **NOT** use your Personal Information to create a blacklist or to make a decision.

#### Find out more

You can contact the 3 credit referencing agencies currently operating in the UK. They will charge you a small statutory fee for giving you a copy of your credit record.

  * CallCredit, Consumer Services Team, PO Box 491, Leeds, LS3 1WZ or call 0870 0601414
  * Equifax PLC, Credit File Advice Centre, PO Box 3001, Bradford, BD1 5US or call 0870 010 0583 or log on to www.myequifax.co.uk
  * Experian, Consumer Help Service, PO Box 8000, Nottingham NG80 7WF or call 0870 241 6212 or log on to www.experian.co.uk

If you have been refused credit you can get advice from your local Trading Standards Department, Citizens Advice Bureau or Consumer Advice Centre and the agencies’ web sites. The Information Commissioner also produces a useful leaflet entitled ‘Credit Explained’. You can obtain a free copy on the Commissioner’s website (www.ico.gov.uk) or by telephoning 0870 600 8100.

#### Fraud Prevention Agencies

We have systems that protect our customers and ourselves against fraud and other crime. Customer information can be used to prevent crime and trace those responsible. If false or inaccurate information is provided and fraud is identified, details will be passed to fraud prevention agencies. Law enforcement agencies may access and use this information. We and other organisations may also access and use this information to prevent fraud and money laundering.

We and other organisations may access and use the information recorded by fraud prevention agencies from other countries.

### Part 3 – Bank Statements

If you’re applying for a Personal Loan online, you will have the ability to share the required bank statements with us, via a 3rd party provider.

You are not required to provide us with viewing access to your bank account transaction information **(Transaction History)** or internet banking access details. You may still be allowed to apply for a loan with us if you do not provide us with this information. However, if you do it will help us make an informed decision about whether we can lend to you.

If you agree that we may access your Transaction History the following provisions shall apply.

**Provide Accurate Information**. You, agree to provide true, accurate, current and complete information about yourself and your bank accounts (with us or third parties) and you agree to not misrepresent your identity or your account information. You agree to keep your bank account information up-to-date, accurate and complete.

**Purposes**. We will access your Transaction History using the services of a credit reference agency called Perfect Data Solutions Limited ( **PDS** ). We will use your Transaction History to assess your creditworthiness and whether the loan you seek is affordable.

Neither we nor PDS will store or have access to your internet banking credentials, PIN codes or passwords. That information is encrypted in transit and stored by a third party service provider upon their servers in a secure environment outside the EEA.

**Third Party Accounts**. By agreeing to allow us viewing access to your Transaction History, you authorise PDS and PDS’s service providers to access third party sites designated by you, on your behalf, to retrieve information requested by us, and to register to view bank statements over a period of up to 90 days. You agree that PDS and PDS’s service providers may, and are instructed by you as your agent and nominated representative, with full power of substitution and re-substitution, for you and in your name, place and stead, in any and all capacities, to access third party internet sites, servers or documents, retrieve information, and use your information, all as described above, with the full power and authority to do and perform each and every act and thing requisite and necessary to be done in connection with such activities, as fully to all intents and purposes as you might or could do in person. This will include the following purposes: copying Transaction History over a 90 day period and transmitting the copied Transaction History via our servers.

You acknowledge and agree that when we, PDS or PDS’s service providers access and retrieve information and Transaction History from third party sites, this is undertaken as your agent, and not the agent on behalf of any third party (including the bank account provider). You should be aware that third party account providers shall be entitled to rely on this authorisation and agency granted by you. You should also be aware that this service is not endorsed or sponsored by any third party bank account providers. We would recommend that you refer to the terms and conditions of your internet banking provider if you would like more information.

You understand that allowing us to review your Transaction History is at your sole risk.

We are only able to review your Transaction History on an “as is” and “as available basis” as it is made available to us by service providers. It may not be available to us from time to time.

We cannot guarantee that allowing us to review your Transaction History will guarantee the success of your loan application or the rate at which the loan is available. The Lender shall include the following prescribed questions and answers within the Website:

**1\. Why do you ask for my internet-banking details?  
**By inputting your details we are able to view up to 90 days of bank account history. This helps us make our lending decisions, assessing whether and if so what amount of credit is affordable and sustainable for you. As a responsible lender, we work with credit reference agencies to review your creditworthiness. As part of that process it is important for us to verify your incomings and outgoings. Ultimately, this will help us ensure that you do not fall in difficulties in making the repayments due under a loan or incurring further costs and charges. We are only permitted a read­only access to your current account, so will only ever be able to view the recent transactions on your account -nothing more. Your bank details are encrypted in transit and stored securely by our credit reference agency and its services providers. We do not have the ability to change any of your banking details, set up standing orders/direct debits or to manage your account in any other way. All data is securely handled in accordance with data protection laws and our privacy policy.

**2\. Who sees my internet banking log-in details?  
**No person can access your internet banking details. When you enter your banking credentials on our website they are securely transmitted. The encrypted details are then passed by our credit reference agency, Perfect Data Solutions Limited and associated service providers. They are stored in a highly secure data centre which has a single use, which is to generate a read-only data-feed which we will use to assess the affordability of the loan.

**3\. What happens to my internet banking details after inputting them on your website?  
**As an organisation, security of data and prevention of fraud are fundamental to us. We are committed to using practices to ensure that our services are provided within a secure environment. Your internet banking details are encrypted and held securely by our professional service providers. Our credit reference agency partner, Perfect Data Solutions Limited and us, are permitted read-only access to your current account, so will only ever be able to view your account.

We do not have the ability to change any of your banking details or set up standing orders/direct debits. All data is securely handled in accordance with data protection laws and our privacy policy.

**4\. What happens to the bank statements you obtain?  
**They will be used by use to make lending decisions about you and stored by us as long as necessary to assist us in managing your account or underwriting loan to you.

**5\. What will my bank say about me inputting my log-in details into your website?  
**We would recommend that you review the Terms and Conditions of your internet banking provider. Before you decide to submit your baking credentials, we would stress that security is of paramount importance, we would especially mention that:

  * Your data is encrypted in transit;
  * We do not have any functionality over your bank account; and
  * We only have access to a read-only service.

Should PDS be directed specifically by Yodlee to ensure the following is actioned, The Lender shall within 60 days of having received written notice from PDS include the following prescribed data protection terms within Loan Agreements.

If you agreed to provide us with viewing access to your internet baking account the following data protection provisions shall apply.

**Provide Accurate Information**. You have provided true, accurate, current and complete information about yourself and your bank accounts (with us or third parties) and you have not misrepresented your identity or your account information.

**Purposes**. We will access your bank account transaction information going back for a period of up to 90 days ( **Transaction History** ) using the services of a credit reference agency called Perfect Data Solutions Limited ( **PDS** ). We will use your Transaction History to assess your creditworthiness and whether the loan you seek is affordable.

Neither we nor PDS will store or have access to your internet banking credentials, PIN codes or passwords. That information is encrypted in transit and stored by a third party service provider upon their servers in a secure environment outside the European Economic Area.

**Third Party Accounts**. By agreeing to allow us viewing access to your Transaction History, you authorise PDS and PDS’s service providers to access third party sites designated by you, on your behalf, to retrieve information requested by us, and to register to view bank statements over a period of up to 90 days. You agree that PDS and PDS’s service providers may, and are instructed by you as your agent and nominated representative, with fall power of substitution and re-substitution, for you and in your name, place and stead, in any and all capacities, to access third party internet sites, servers or documents, retrieve information, and use your information, all as described above, with the full power and authority to do and perform each and every act and thing requisite and necessary to be done in connection with such activities, as folly to all intents and purposes as you might or could do in person. This will include the following purposes: copying Transaction History over a 90 day period and transmitting the copied Transaction History via our servers.

You acknowledge and agree that when we, PDS or PDS’s service providers access and retrieve information and Transaction History from third party sites, this is undertaken as your agent, and not the agent on behalf of any third party (including the bank account provider). You should be aware that third party account providers shall be entitled to rely on this authorisation and agency granted by you. You should also be aware that this service is not endorsed or sponsored by any third party bank account providers. We would recommend that you refer to the terms and conditions of your internet banking provider if you would like more information.

You understand that allowing us to review your Transaction History is at your sole risk.

We are only able to review your Transaction History on an “as is” and “as available basis” as it is made available to us by service providers. It may not be available to us from time to time.

Last Updated: 02/2016
